

STEPHEN PEARCE

Junior Gameplay Programmer

Games: Code: Network:

Home:

https://stevepdp.dev https://stevepdp.itch.io https://github.com/stevepdp

https://linkedin.com/in/stevepdp

Swaffham, Norfolk

hello@stevepdp.dev Open to assisted relocation within England

https://linktr.ee/stevepdp

Brief

I have 3 years experience with C# & Unity. This is evidenced by a portfolio of games, public source code and a range of digital certificates. To improve my case for breaking-in to the industry, this year I participated in a gameplay programming bootcamp with Mastered, guided by Unity-authorised mentors and career coaches, I'm now applying to full-time and temp/fixed-term contract roles where I can hone my skills, contribute to hit games and climb the ranks my discipline.

Relevant Experience

- 16+ weeks major Unity project development at Mastered with weekly one-to-one mentoring. Also four monthly creator challenges, each simulating a live production scenario. Utilising Slack, Zoom & Trello for communication.
- Independent participation in 8+ game jams, with optimised builds playable either natively or via web browser.
- 11+ digital certificates in games business, design and development. Recently: Godot, C++ and Unity Learn.
- Actively learning C++ and Godot Engine, utilising Zenva and Sololearn courseware.

Technical Skills

<u>Unity</u> – Scene flow, prefabs, sprites, animation, particles, input, Navmesh, project / editor / player settings, editor tools, debugger, raw asset imports, Unity Asset Store, package management, UlBuilder, ProBuilder, Photon multiplayer.

C# - Proficient in OOP principles: abstraction, inheritance, polymorphism & encapsulation. SOLID principles. Popular game programming patterns. Events. Persisting data and data-driven logic. Profiling & performance optimisation.

C++ - Good understanding of C++. MSYS2 (Windows) and WSL2 (Ubuntu) build environments. Custom toolchains, make scripts, GNU compilers, static / dynamic linking and paths, debugging, leak detection, dependency tools.

<u>Version Control</u> – Experience with Git, GitHub, and GitLab. Understanding of branching models. Following code style and commit conventions, filing issues, pull requests, writing documentation, organisations / permissions and API integration.

Production Lifecycle – Agile development among multi-disciplinary and on-site distributed teams. Sprint planning, prototyping, development, documenting, stand-up and retrospectives. Collaborating via Trello, Jira, Confluence & Sheets.

Soft Skills

Flexible Learner – I'm a guick and enthusiastic self-learner. Utilising primarily web resources, I adapt to new tools and technologies with ease and often under time pressures. I've learned to utilize ChatGPT as a coach and reasoning aid too.

Focused and Disciplined - I thoroughly investigate and break problems down, applying Deep Work practices to tackle the workload. I also use Kanban tools to backlog and queue tasks, communicate my progress and reflect on progress made.

<u>Collaborative</u> – Using Slack, Zoom and Miro I've teamed-up for coding, ideation, strategy and design thinking sessions. Often this requires patience and the ability to debate, manage conflict and find common ground among differing views.

Education & Professional Development

Intermediate C++ Unity Learn – Junior Programmer Foundation Degree in Business Computing

Digital certificate issued by SoloLearn, August 2023 Digital certificate issued by Unity Technologies, June 2023 City College Norwich (UEA), 2006-2009

Employment History

Web Developer Web Developer Information Technology Manager

Sidekick Digital, November 2015 – July 2021 Binarydrive, June 2013 - November 2015 Overburys Solicitors, July 2010 – September 2012